bremer.com 2014-07-04

# 

                                                                                                                             Rev. 09/13
                                                                                               Privacy Statement
                      WHAT DOES BREMER BANK, NATIONAL ASSOCIATION (“BREMER”)
FACTS                 DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
               Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to
Why?           limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share and protect your
               personal information. Please read this statement carefully to understand what we do.
               The type of personal information we collect and share depends on the product or service you have with us. This
What?          information can include:
                      Identification information, such as your name, address, birth date, Social Security number and driver’s
                      license number.
                      Application information we receive from you when you request a product or service, such as your income,
                      assets and liabilities.
                      Transactions or experiences with us, such as your current balances or repayment history.
                      Transactions or experiences with others.
                      Information we receive from consumer reporting agencies, such as credit bureaus.
               All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the
How?           section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the
               reasons Bremer chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.
                                                                                                                Does       Can you
Reasons we can share your personal information                                                                 Bremer      limit this
                                                                                                               share?      sharing?
For our everyday business purposes – such as to process your transactions, maintain your                         Yes          No
account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or to report to credit bureaus.
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your transactions and
experiences.                                                                                                     Yes          Yes
For our marketing purposes – for us to offer our products and services to you.                                   Yes          Yes
For non-affiliates to market to you on our behalf – to the extent permitted by law, Bremer may
share our application, identification, and Bremer transactional or experience information with other
companies we employ to help us perform marketing services. Examples of these companies include
                                                                                                                 Yes          Yes
telemarketing and direct sales companies. All companies we employ are contractually obligated to
keep the information we that provide to them confidential. In addition, the information they receive from
us may be used only to provide the services we request.
For our affiliates to market to you – if we feel you may benefit from products and services offered by
a Bremer company, we may share the following information about you:
         Identification information                Bremer-related transactional or experience information        Yes          Yes
         Application information                   Third-party related transactional or experience
         Consumer report information               information
For joint marketing purposes – to offer products and services from non-affiliates. We may share
your identification and transactional or experience information with other financial services providers
with whom we have joint marketing agreements. Examples include credit card companies, investment
                                                                                                                 Yes          Yes
brokerage companies and insurance companies. These companies are contractually obligated to keep
the information that we provide to them confidential. In addition, the information they receive from us
may be used only for specific joint marketing purposes.
To limit our sharing, or                    Call us toll-free at 800-908-BANK (2265).
if you have questions

Page 2
Who we are
Who is providing this notice?          Bremer Bank, National Association
What we do
                                       The information we collect and record is protected by physical, electronic, and procedural
How does Bremer protect my             measures that comply with federal regulations. Only those employees who need this
personal information?                  information to service your account or provide you with products and services are granted
                                       access.
                                       We collect your personal information, for example, when you
                                             Open an account or deposit money
How does Bremer collect my                   Pay your bills or apply for a loan
personal information?                        Use your credit or debit card
                                       We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or
                                       other companies.
                                       Federal law gives you the right to limit only
                                             Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes- information about your
                                             creditworthiness.
Why can’t I limit all sharing?               Affiliates from using your information to market to you.
                                             Sharing for non-affiliates to market to you.
                                       State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. (See
                                       below for more on your rights under state law.)
What happens when I limit
sharing for an account I hold          Your choices will apply individually, unless you tell us otherwise.
jointly with someone else?
Definitions
                                       Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and
Affiliates                             nonfinancial companies: Bremer Trust; Bremer Insurance; Bremer Financial Services, Inc;
                                       Other bank charters owned by Bremer Financial Corporation
                                       Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and
Nonaffiliates
                                       nonfinancial companies.
                                       A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market
Joint Marketing
                                       financial products or services to you.
Other Important Information
This Privacy Statement can be obtained at any Bremer location or on Bremer.com. In addition, this notice is given to any new
consumer client opening an account and is mailed to consumer clients on an annual basis as required by law. Any updates or
material changes to this Privacy Statement will be posted on Bremer.com, and the last date of modification will be noted.
Updates or material changes will also be reflected in the notice mailed to consumer clients on an annual basis.
Important Notice for North Dakota Residents and Businesses: North Dakota places additional limitations on sharing
information about North Dakota residents and businesses. In accordance with North Dakota law, Bremer will not share
information we collect about North Dakota residents or businesses except:
      As permitted by law,
      To companies that perform services on our behalf, or
      With the written authorization or consent of the North Dakota resident or business.
Follow these steps to safeguard your financial information:
      Before revealing personal financial information, find out how it will be used and if it will be shared with others. Provide your
      confidential information only when absolutely necessary.
      If you’ve been a victim of identify theft, file a complaint with the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.
                                                                                                                           BFS-014-0913
